<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Developer | Junerey Casuga]]></title>
  <link href="http://junereycasuga.github.io/blog/categories/developer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://junereycasuga.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T20:25:04+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://junereycasuga.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Junerey Casuga]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[junerey.casuga@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Rants: Git Commit Messages]]></title>
    <link href="http://junereycasuga.github.io/blog/2014/05/15/developer-rants-git-commit-messages/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-15T20:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://junereycasuga.github.io/blog/2014/05/15/developer-rants-git-commit-messages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This will be my first post for my Developer Rants series. It will be a series of blog posts of me ranting about some issues or problems I encounter while developing some apps.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Okay, obviously on this first post, I will be talking about Git commit messages.</p>

<h3>It&rsquo;s not funny</h3>

<p>My team is currently developing an app for our company. Being the team lead and head of my department, I always check the commits and pushes of my team on our repository. And I suddenly saw a non-sense commit message. And I&rsquo;m like, WTF was that!? When I check the changes on that specific commit, it was just a class added on an HTML element. I got really annoyed with what I saw. Some may see this as a funny commit message, but dude, it&rsquo;s a serious business, so it&rsquo;s not funny. Yea, I admit that I&rsquo;m also doing it before on my personal projects. But for maturity and professionalism&rsquo;s sake, please take commit messages seriously.</p>

<h3>Proper commit message is important</h3>

<p>Proper git commit messages are important. Why?</p>

<ol>
<li>It speeds up reviewing process.</li>
<li>To help other developers to understand what changes has been made on a specific commit.</li>
<li>It is helpful for documenting changes on your project.</li>
</ol>


<p><blockquote><p>Everybody has terrible commit messages in some point in their life.</p></p><p><p>Sometimes every single day.</p><footer><strong>Zac Holman</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<h3>Making a better Git commit</h3>

<p>If you are reading this. And you feel like you&rsquo;re the one I&rsquo;m referring to, you still have the chance to change this bad habit.</p>

<p>I am annoyed seeing a &lsquo;bug fix&rsquo; commit messages. It&rsquo;s too broad. And I don&rsquo;t even know what bug was fixed and where it was located.</p>

<p>To make it better, try to limit using <code>git commit -m "Some crappy commit message here"</code>. Better to use <code>git commit</code> with no flags. By using a simpler git commit command, it will open up Vim (if it&rsquo;s your default editor) where you can construct a better commit message.</p>

<p>Structure your commit message like this:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Short summary of changes (50 chars or less and don&rsquo;t put period at the end)&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>More detailed description of the changes. This will be good place to
</span><span class='line'>explain what has been changed and why it has been changed. The text
</span><span class='line'>should be wrapped at 72 chars.</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Sorry for the rant. It just really annoys me. Anyways, Happy commiting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
